## Filbert Shi

New York, NY - 718-687-3038 - contact@filbert.io

Website: filbert.io - LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/filbert-shi/ - Github: github.com/Sporego

# **Summary**

Full-stack Engineer with a background in aerospace and software engineering, and one year of professional experience designing, developing, and deploying full-stack web applications with intuitive and mobile-responsive user interfaces (UI). Semiprofessional Esports team leader and strategic planner reaching 36th international ranking.

### **Skills**

- Programming Languages: Typescript, JavaScript, C#, Python, R
- Web Development: Node.js, HTML, CSS, jQuery, Sass, RESTful API
- Front End: Angular, React, Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap
- Back End: PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Redis
- Tools: Git, Apache Subversion (SVN), Yarn, NPM, Docker, Kubernetes
- Cloud: Heroku, Amazon Web Services (AWS), Vercel, Google Cloud Platform (GCP)

# **Experience**

Full Stack Engineer, Eric Adams 2021 (ericadams2021.com), New York, NY 09/2020 - Present

- Convinced Brooklyn Borough President Eric and his team of my vision for his NYC mayoral campaign website
- Cut initial costs by 100% and monthly costs by 75% by persuading the marketing team to abstain from WordPress with plugins, and instead use a tech stack consisting of Node.js, React, Next.js, and MongoDB
- Initiated and completed documentation for all React components and API endpoints, as well as OPSEC guidelines
- Improved mean and median time spent by 50% and 66% via running A/B tests in collaboration with a data analyst
- Integrated Google Analytics, Tag Manager, and Mailchimp Marketing for data collection and advertising to over 9000+ unique monthly visitors (over +300 visitors per day)
- Ensured accessibility of visitors by applying user persona model and creating three mobile responsive layout widths

#### Full Stack Engineer, Festival Advisor (festivaladvisor.com), New York, NY 03/2020 - 12/2020

- Slashed operating cost by 50% by moving to Serverless architecture via AWS S3, CloudFront, and Lambda
- Integrated Contentful (Headless CMS) UI-Extensions to validate data with Spotify's API for editors
- Optimized SEO by finding and addressing deficiencies detected through Google Rich Results Tests
- Designed and presented front-end prototypes in Figma prior to implementation of React components and route
- Migrated 80% of codebase from JavaScript to TypeScript
- Collaborated with a small team in a startup environment to build ambitious and challenging features from scratch

### **Technology Coordinator, DreamHack Montreal, Montreal, Quebec**

09/2018 - 12/2018

- Coordinated with volunteers and facilitated implementation of pfSense firewall with a team of network engineers to secure a RFC1918 production network with 0.5 terabit/s internet connection.
- Assist in testing of node is and electron is based application to manage 100+ computers.

## **Education**

**Columbia University** 

Aerospace System Engineering (60 credits) Computer Science: Full-Stack Development

New York, NY 2019

New York, NY

2015 - 2017

2019

**Bronx Science** 

Diploma with Honors